Guide to the Gertrude Maurin correspondence, 1962-1983 MS 405
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Gertrude Maurin correspondence
1962-1983
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Maurin, Gertrude
MS 405
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection contains correspondence from Gertrude Maurin with Dr. Joseph Banks Rhine, Dr. Louisa E. Rhine, Dr. Marie Higbee Avery, and other individuals connected with the Duke University Parapsychology Laboratory, the Institute for Parapsychology, and the Foundation for Research on the Nature of Man in Durham, North Carolina. Most of the correspondence is incoming, although a few manuscript drafts of outgoing letters exist. Generally, the correspondence concerns Miss Maurin's support of the institutions. Also included are letters from her attorney and bankers.
Biographical / Historical
Gertrude Maurin graduated from Rice University in 1922. She was a long-time supporter and donor to the Duke Parapsychology Lab, later named the Foundation for Research on the Nature of Man (FRNM) and the Institute for Parapsychology. Maurin had a long correspondence with Dr. Joseph Banks Rhine, head of the institute. Maurin mentioned in her letters both her ESP and her apport experiences. She donated more than $20,000 to the institute over a 20 year span.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence from Gertrude Maurin with Dr. Joseph Banks Rhine, Dr. Louisa E. Rhine, Dr. Marie Higbee Avery, and other individuals connected with the Duke University Parapsychology Laboratory, the Institute for Parapsychology, and the Foundation for Research on the Nature of Man in Durham, North Carolina. Most of the correspondence is incoming, although a few manuscript drafts of outgoing letters exist. Generally, the correspondence concerns Miss Maurin's support of the institutions. Also included are letters from her attorney and bankers.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was a gift donated by Miss Gertrude Maurin on June 17, 1987.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Telemetry; Psychical research; Parapsychology; Extrasensory perception; Health care and medicine
Document Types
corrrespondence
Subjects (Persons)
Silva, Jose -- Correspondence; Manning, Matthew -- Correspondence; Huxley, Aldous -- Correspondence; Owen, A. R. G. (Alan Robert George); Rhine, Louisa E. -- Correspondence; Rhine, J.B. (Joseph Banks) -- Correspondence; Mitchell, Edgar D. -- Correspondence; Carrington, Hereward -- Correspondence; Geller, Uri -- Correspondence; Levy, Walter J., Jr. -- Correspondence; Dixon, Jeanne; Sinclair, Upton; Velikovsky, Immanuel -- Correspondence; Jule Eisenbud, M.D. -- Correspondence
Subjects (Corporations)
American Society for Psychical Research; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers
- Series I: Correspondence, 1962 - 1983; 46372
  - Avery, Marie Higbee, correspondence, 1964 - 1970; 1.1; 46373 (Folder 1)
  - Rao, K.R., correspondence, 1980 - 1982; 46374 (Folder 2)
  - Rhine, Joseph Banks, correspondence, 1962 - 1966; 46375 (Folder 3)
  - Rhine, Joseph Banks, correspondence, 1967 - 1969; 46376 (Folder 4)
  - Rhine, Joseph Banks, correspondence, 1970 - 1972; 46377 (Folder 5)
  - Rhine, Joseph Banks, correspondence, 1973 - 1979; 46378 (Folder 6)
  - Rhine, Joseph Banks death, Feb. 20, 1980; 46379 (Folder 7)
  - Rhine, Louisa E., correspondence, 1967 - 1982; 46380 (Folder 8)
  - Rhine, Louisa E. death, March 17, 1983; 46381 (Folder 9)
- Series II: Newspaper Clippings and printed materials, 1962 - 1983, 46382
  - Newspaper Clippings, articles, reviews, 46383 (Folder 10)
  - Foundation for research in the Nature of Man, meeting notices/agendas/minutes, reports, correspondence, 1962 - 1983; 46384 (Folder 11)